Duc D Nguyen

CONTACT

623-570-4113

ndduc1856@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/duc-nguyen-1a5155a2/ github.com/ndduc

STACK

- Stack:
- Java 0
- **Dart** 0
- C# 0
- **Javascript** 0
- **Typescript**
- Php
- Html/Css
- AWS Cloud Service:
 - API gateway (Rest/Https)
 - lambda
 - **RDS Database** 0
 - Dynamodb 0
 - **SNS** 0
 - SQS 0
 - **Cloud Formation**
 - **Cloud Watch**
 - CloudFront
 - Route53 0
- Framework:
 - Flutter 0
 - Ant 0
 - **Bootstrap**
 - **Angular** 0
- Database:
 - MySQL 0
 - MsSQL 0
 - **SQLite** 0
 - **Postgres**
 - ElasticSearch 0
- Git:
- **Github**
- Bitbucket
- **Azure DevOps**
- Test:
- **Angular Karma/Jasmine**
- **C# Moq Unit Test** 0
- **Flutter Integration Test**
- **Android UI Espresso Test**

© OBJECTIVE

An enthusiastic and self-motivated Software Engineer with extensive experience with more than 3 years in designing, developing, and testing large-scale software. Strong background in object-oriented software development. Capable of working in a team environment or working independently. Extensive knowledge of Software Testing, designing, developing, and implementing test plans, test cases, and test

I am continually seeking new challenges and a desire to expand my knowledge and experience.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- Excellent full stack programming ability.
- Designing, implementing, refactoring, and testing code, following best practices for maintainability, testability, and performance.
- Knowledge of standard software development practices (source code control systems, unit testing, debugging, documentation)
- Quick learner and ability to quickly grasp technical/business concepts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | Gearfire

Jul 2021 - Present

Worked with large team of 10+ software engineers and responsible for bringing business's ideas and visions into the reality. I was full-stack engineer and worked on both side of the Ecommerce platform, responsible for developing enterprise scale microservices and apis that act as the infrastructure that support the platform. Responsible for multiple different front-end development such as customer website and admin website.

Gearfire's Ecommerce

- Microservice/Apis
 - o Developed support services such as multiple domain infrastructure that allow user to add and update unlimited number of domains to client application while still ensure both DNS and CloudFront integrities.
 - Developed support services and subscribes for DynamoDB and client application
 - o Developed secured endpoint that allow client to pull and update data from both RDS and NoSQL database.
- Database
 - Designed NoSQL table and strategized the best implementation for primary key, sort key, and GSI based on business logic.
 - o Updated and back filled the existing records in Elasticsearch programmatically with C#
- Ecommerce's client
 - Developed core features and wired-up backend support for multiple clients such as customer website, admin website, and distributor website
- Reference:
 - o https://www.gearfire.com
 - o https://www.gogearfire.com

Developer/Owner | Anime Finder Project

Present

- Non-profit torrent finder application, the highlight point of the app is a visualization and better user experience compared to the text-base UI of the traditional torrent site. The site allows users to browse any existing torrent anime's title both seasonal and classic.
- Application was built with angular and bootstrap, back-end infrastructure is supported by AWS and c#.
- App Site:
 - https://anifinders.com

- Performed unit testing, integration testing, system testing, actively involved in the testing of the application, and resolving technical issues.
- Designed and coded several systems to communicate with vendors to their specifications.
- Lead Mobile Application Engineer, responsible for planning and developing multiple mobile applications for Embry Health. I am specialized in hybrid application development such as Flutter/Dart which can be deployed to production at a much faster pace on multiple platforms as well as creating a highly reusable codebase. Expertise in strategizes and planning application model, UX/UI, and integrating backend support such as Rest API, AWS Appsync GQL, AWS API Gateway.
- Experienced with application deployment on both Apple and Google store, as well as experienced with distributing the application privately through MS Intune.

Embry Health's Projects

• Embry Field Application

 Provided a faster and more accurate workflow for the field employees who were tasked to create an appointment and check-in patients at Covid testing events and other general medical facilities.

• Embry Patient Facing Application

- Application was created to give customer an alternative way to book and manage their medical appointment.
 - Google Play Store
 - https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.embryhealth.patient
 - Apple Store
 - https://apps.apple.com/us/app/embry-health-patient-app/id1552480515

Vaxtrack – Vaccine Tracking Application

- Vaxtrack is an internal vaccine tracking application. Introducing feature such as checking in and out Covid-19 vaccine and systematically distribute to patient.
- App Screenshots:
- https://docs.google.com/document/d/1rt6AKaBFOd6rpSE6KOGRAbiafx3ed6P59Zpx7Uhzr5Y/edit?usp=sharing

• Embry Eye - Internal GPS device tracking

- o Device tracking application that designed to run on device's background.
- App Screenshots:
- o https://docs.google.com/document/d/1eTJNVArs GKhGgyKtqHtSN6KLHZ2pcMgnIWkqTCM1QM/edit?usp=sharing

Embry Asset – Asset Inventory Tracking

- Overall company inventory control application.
- App Screenshots:
- o https://docs.google.com/document/d/1nhXWgttO-U9 3e3-rjJ5ZqAW754fVZhneLmXWTWy9Cg/edit?usp=sharing

Full Stack Developer/Database Administrator | SoftPoint LLC

Jun 2020 - Nov 2020

- Administered database security by creating user logins to different project staff with appropriate roles and monitoring the user accounts.
- Responsible for creating and maintaining the purging process for 300+ tables and millions of records for all databases.
- Developed database structure, implement applications, enhance the system and ensure security.
- Developed/programmed new functionality and features in line with functional specifications and business requirements.
- Created and maintaining the clustering process, which allows to copy or move all records of specific conditions from one database to another database.
- Worked on dynamic screen sizing for POS applications on tablet devices.
- Implemented a feature call Flash that allows the POS application to render a web interface and giving users full control on an Android view.

Price Analyst/Software Developer | Lee Lee International Market

Jun-2017 - Jun-2020

- Conducted model pricing scenarios and negotiating agreements that maximize benefits and minimizing the corporative risks.
- Prepared and analyzed request--for--proposal responses, including the development of pricing strategies and revenue streams for accounts.
- Developed POS cross-platform back-end application with Java, that was deployed on multiple environments like Windows, and Linux. Featuring core features that focus on the efficiency of data entry.
- Developed Customer facing product search application in form of an internal Web application (PHP, and MsSQL) that was the plan to be installed across the company's facilities for both customers and employees to look up the existing products.
- Developed Labelling application on Android platform and utilized both Zebra and DYMO technologies.

EDUCATION

Arizona State University 2018-2021

B.S – Software Engineering GPA: 3.4

Mesa Community College 2015-2017

A.A.S – Computer Programming GPA: 3.6

REFERENCES

Brian Blank

- Project Manager At TestNow Embry Health
- 602-370-6652

Arron Bohelm

- Project Manager At TestNow Embry Health
- 480-433-2715